A Guide to the Aaron Family Collection, 1908-1927
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Aaron Family Collection, 1908-1927
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1968-004
1.4 cu. ft. 3 boxes
College memorabilia, including photographs, printed material, and banners collected by John H., Jacob C., and Harry B. Aaron, three Bristol, Virginia brothers who attended Virginia Tech during the early 20th century.
Aaron family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Aaron Family Collection was donated to Newman Library in 1968.
Biographical Note
John Henry Aaron, the third child of Christopher and Laura Giles Aaron, was born on February 11, 1889. He graduated from Virginia Tech in 1910 with a degree in applied chemistry. In 1918, Aaron was living in City Point, Virginia, where he married Emily Graves Bland (1890-1957) and was employed as an assistant chief chemist. By 1929, Aaron was living in Wilmington, Delaware. In 1935, he was living in Penns Grove, New Jersey and was working as a chemist for DuPont. John H. Aaron died in Wilmington, Delaware on December 5, 1953. He was buried in Blandford Cemetery, Petersburg, Virginia.
Jacob Carr Aaron, younger brother of John Henry Aaron, was born in 1894. Aaron attended officer training school at the beginning of World War I and served in the infantry throughout the war. In 1920, he graduated from Virginia Tech with a degree in chemical engineering. The census of that year found him living with his parents in Bristol, Virginia and working as a bookkeeper. He married Glenna King in 1921. Still in Bristol in 1935, he was employed as secretary-treasurer of Morley Bros. & Company, a produce distribution business. Aaron later became the company's manager and continued in that position until 1958, when the company dissolved. He later worked as secretary of Hulsey Flooring Service. Jacob C. Aaron died in February, 1971.
Harry Bertram Aaron, another son of Christopher and Laura Giles Aaron, was born in 1895. In 1917, Aaron graduated from the Artillery Training School and as a member of the Artillery Reserve Corps was immediately assigned to duty in France. He graduated from Virginia Tech in 1919 with a degree in mining engineering. The 1920 census places him in the Bristol, Virginia home of his parents, with no occupation.The 1930 census shows him still living in the home of his parents and the proprietor of a filling station. Aaron was still in Bristol as of 1935 and was working as a statistical clerk for the National Reemployment Service. He died before 1971.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains college memorabilia of John H., Jacob C., and Harry B. Aaron, three brothers from Bristol, Virginia who attended Virginia Tech in the early 20th century. Among the materials included within the collection are printed materials, photographs, textiles and ephemera.
The collection contains a small, leather calling card case, bearing a VPI insignia. Also included are Virginia Tech commencement programs from 1908 and 1909, and a 1909 satirical publication titled "The Horn," poking fun at the school's administration and faculty. Other printed materials in the collection are two calendars, illustrated with photographs of campus scenes.
Also containing photos of campus scenes is an album compiled by Harry B. Aaron while a student at Virginia Tech. The album includes pictures of friends and classmates; cadets in formation and on parade; campus buildings; football games against Washington and Lee University and Virginia Military Institute; a track meet against North Carolina A&M; a campus snow battle; the 1919 Virginia Tech baseball team; and the surrounding area (including Brush Mountain and Mountain Lake); as well as Big Creek and Abraham Falls, near Bristol, Virginia.
The collection also contains two pennants, a banner, and a pillowcase, all bearing Virginia Tech designs.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by material type.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
The following items were transferred to the Photograph Collection when the Aaron Family Collection was accessioned:
Harry B. Aaron and nine other students in civilian clothes (see "Students, 1900-1930")
Football squad, 1915 (see "Football, 1910-1920")
Football team, 1915-1917 (see "Football, 1910-1920")
Football team, 1915-1917 (see "Football, 1910-1920")
Company B, 1915-1916 (see "Corps - Company B")
Cotillion Club, 1915-1916 (see "Cotillion Club")
Index Terms
Subjects:
Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute
Local Subjects:
University Archives
Contents List
- Leather calling card case, n.d. (Box-item 1-1)
- Commencement programs
  - 1908 (Box-item 1-2)
  - 1909 (Box-item 1-3)
- Photo album, 1913-1916, n.d. (Box-item 1-4)
- "The Horn," 1909 (Box-item 1-5)
- Calendars
  - 1916 (Box-item 1-6)
  - 1917 (Box-item 1-7)
- "The Bayonet" pictorial section, Mar 15 1918 (Box-item 1-8)
- Banner ("Virginia Polytechnic Inst."), n.d. (Box-item 2-1)
- Pennants
  - "Va. Tech," 1927 (Box-item 3-1)
  - "V.P.I.," n.d. (Box-item 3-2)
- Pillowcase ("V.P.I."), n.d. (Box-item 3-3)